(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners,
and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- Hi, everyone.
My name is Katherine,
and today we have another
episode of our
interview series lessons.
- That's right, today we're taking a look
at a very important aspect of an interview.
We're talking about salary and money.
- That's right, so this is
the end of the interview,
when we're starting to
talk about details of the job.
Let's check this out, listen
to the dialogue one time,
and when we come back, we'll be
talking more about what's going on.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, well I'm sure
you have a number of
questions to ask me
regarding the position.
- Yes, well, Ms. Charles did give me an
overview of the position over the phone,
but there were some
details I'd like to clarify.
- Well, feel free to ask me anything,
and I'll try to fill in the details.
- Could I first ask about
the renumeration package?
- Yes, of course, that's quite
an important point, is it it?
As the junior sub editor, we offer a
starting salary of $150,000 per annum.
This doesn't include a
generous housing allowance also.
- I understand, and are
there other bonuses included?
- Well, apart from full health insurance,
we do offer a company
staff bonus scheme link
to readership numbers,
but we could go through
all the details of
that at a later date.
- Well, Ms. Parsons, I am
flexible when it comes to salary.
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong
with your company is the
most important thing for me.
- Excellent.
Well, what other questions
do you have, Rebecca?
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back,
so let's take a look
at a couple of words and
phrases on language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, so this first
phrase is a set phrase,
that means these
words often go together.
Other phrases, remuneration package.
- That's right, a remuneration package.
Rebecca said, "Could I first ask
about the remuneration package?
" - So it's an easier
way to say this, Marco.
- I guess basically the salary.
- That's right.
But a package means
that it's not just money,
it's also some of the
benefits or the bonuses.
So this is a way to describe
how a person is paid in general.
- That's right.
So the remuneration package
that Rebecca is being offered,
Mr. Parsons said that she would get a
starting salary of $150,000 per annum.
- Okay, so this phrase starting salary
is another fixed phrase,
we have a lot of these today.
That means these two words
go together starting salary.
So salary is easy, it's the amount of money
you make either per month
or per week or per year.
But what is a starting
salary, how is that different?
- Well, basically that's the money that
you would start earning in the company.
But obviously with time it could
change and you can get more money.
- So this means that you will
start making this much money
but it's possible that in the
future you will make more.
This is the starting salary.
- That's right.
And well, of course, as we said, it's
$150,000 Hong Kong dollars per annum.
So now we're specifying how often
you're getting this money per annum.
- So if it were per month,
this might be a lot of money.
- That's right.
- This is how much money
she will earn per year per annum.
This comes from Latin.
- That's right, so per year.
So this is the remuneration
package she's getting.
Not only is she getting $150,000 per annum,
she's also getting a housing allowance.
- Okay, so many of us had
allowances when we were children.
This means the money that your
parents gave you each week, $5 or $10.
Well, a housing allowance
is a little bit different.
It means the money that your
company gives you per month
or per year to pay for your
apartment or your house.
- That's right.
So obviously the company is saying that,
look, we're gonna give you a certain amount
of money for you to pay for your house.
You don't have to
really pay for your house.
We'll pay for it.
- So basically it's a benefit.
It's a part of this remuneration package
you get a salary and you
get money for your house.
It's a pretty nice deal.
- That's right.
And well, also she's
getting health insurance
and she is also being offered a
company's staff bonus scheme.
- Okay, bonus scheme.
A bonus is something extra.
It's on top of what you normally get.
But a bonus scheme indicates that the
bonus changes according to how well you do.
- That's right.
So obviously he's specifying that the bonus
scheme is linked to readership numbers.
- So let's say, for example,
Marco sells newspapers.
Marco, you sell on a
good week 100 newspapers.
If you sell 150, you get a bonus of $10.
That's right.
- But if you sell 200 newspapers,
you get a bonus of $50.
- That's right.
- This is a scheme, the numbers change.
- Very good.
So all of this that we've just talked about,
to be clear is our remuneration package.
We're talking about a salary.
We're talking about housing allowance,
health insurance, and even a bonus scheme.
So a package can include these things
and much, much more CEOs
get bigger remuneration packages.
- They do.
And if you had children,
sometimes a part of your package
is education costs for your children,
or a car or computers, things like that.
- That's right.
So a lot of great stuff
there talking about
salaries and a little
bit of negotiating it.
Why don't we go back, listen to the
dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, well I'm sure
you have a number of
questions to ask me
regarding the position.
- Yes, well Ms. Charles did give me an
overview of the position over the phone,
but there were some
details I'd like to clarify.
- Well, feel free to ask me anything
and I'll try to fill in the details.
- Could I first ask about
the remuneration package?
- Yes, of course, that's quite
an important point, is it it?
As the junior sub
editor, we offer a starting
salary of 150,000 Hong
Kong dollars per annum.
This doesn't include a
generous housing allowance also.
- I understand.
And are there other bonuses included?
- Well, apart from full
health insurance, we do offer a
company's staff bonus scheme
linked to readership numbers.
But we could go through all
the details of that at a later date.
- Well, Ms. Parsons, I am
flexible when it comes to salary.
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong
with your company is the
most important thing for me.
- Excellent.
Well, what other questions
do you have, Rebecca?
All right, so now let's take
a look at fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
So at the beginning of the dialogue, Rebecca
is talking to Mr. Parsons about the job.
And she says, you know, I don't really have
that many questions,
but when I talked to Ms.
Childs about the job over the phone, there
were some things she wanted to clarify.
So how did she talk to her?
She talked to her over the phone.
- That's right.
- This is a really good phrase to
specify that you received information
or you did business talking
on the phone, not in person.
- Okay, so this is a bit strange
because we use the preposition over.
You could also say, I'm on the phone.
That means I'm talking on the phone.
But over the phone means by phone.
- That's right.
- Not by mail or email or in person,
but we communicate, we
talk over the phone by phone.
So sometimes for example,
people will see a TV commercial
with a nice item or device
that they want to buy and they
will purchase this object, maybe
a DVD player over the phone.
They will call up this number and order it.
- That's it, or you can say, you know,
I'm really sorry, Marco,
but I don't feel comfortable
talking about my banking
details over the phone.
- That's right.
Okay, so that means on the phone.
So then Mr. Parsons said,
feel free to ask me anything,
okay, feel free to ask me
anything about the job.
- Okay, this is a phrase that I use all
the time and I think it's really important
when you're in a business
context or a work context
to say, listen, if you have
any questions, feel free to ask.
It means don't hesitate, don't be nervous.
If you have a question, just ask it.
- That's right, so feel free to ask.
Don't worry about it, just ask me.
It's a very good phrase to give someone
or to make someone feel
more comfortable around.
- Exactly, exactly.
- All right, and he said that
I'll try to fill in the details.
- Okay, so this is an interesting phrase
because fill in, you know,
on a form, for example,
means put your name in a
box or fill in some numbers.
But here, the details, we think maybe
I don't know what the details are.
So to fill them in means to
fill in gaps or some blanks.
So like, I don't know all the details,
please tell me the information
so that I will know them.
- That's right.
Well, what he's basically saying is,
I know that you have an
idea or a general overview
of how things are, but
if you ask me, I can tell
you more specific things
that fill in the details.
- Or for example, we're
going to a party on Saturday
night, but I don't know
where the party is yet.
How about on Friday, I call
you to fill you in on the details.
- Very good.
Okay, so those are the phrases
that we've prepared for you today.
I think we've taken a
look at a lot of great vocab,
but we listened to the
dialogue one last time
and we'll be back to talk
to you a little bit more.
- Okay, well, I'm sure
you have a number of
questions to ask me
regarding the position.
- Yes, well, Ms. Charles did give me an
overview of the position over the phone,
but there were some
details I'd like to clarify.
- Well, feel free to ask me anything,
and I'll try to fill in the details.
- Could I first ask about
the renumeration package?
- Yes, of course, that's quite
an important point, is it it?
As a junior sub-editor, we offer a
starting salary of $150,000 per annum.
This doesn't include a
generous housing allowance also.
- I understand.
And are there other bonuses included?
- Well, apart from full health insurance,
we do offer a company staff bonus
scheme linked to readership numbers,
but we could go through all
the details of that at a later date.
- Well, Ms. Parsons, I am
flexible when it comes to salary.
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong
with your company is the
most important thing for me.
- Excellent.
Well, what other questions
do you have, Rebecca?
(upbeat music)
- All right, so talking about
salaries and remuneration packages.
Now, is this a common word
to talk about remuneration?
- Yes, it is.
It basically means the way that
you are paid for the work that you do.
- So remuneration, it
sounds like a big long word.
But in America, I think we also just
talk about salary or compensation.
- Compensation packages.
Okay, so now when we
talk about remuneration,
we don't necessarily always talk
about money, like in this case, right?
We can receive other benefits.
- That's right.
And so a lot of times people
think of the important parts
of remuneration, not just to be
the salary, but also to be the benefits.
And so benefits are not the
money, they're the other stuff.
They're healthcare.
We said earlier, a housing allowance,
even bonuses and things like that,
or education for your
children, these are
extras, and these are
a part of the package.
- Now, what would you prefer to
have a good remuneration package,
like these other additional
benefits with a low
salary, or would you
prefer to have a high salary
with no, not many of these benefits?
- Well, I think that it's
nice to get the benefits
and a lower salary, because
oftentimes at a company,
like a big company, the company
can get really good rates on healthcare.
So if I have to pay for
my healthcare with my
big salary, maybe it will
cost me more money.
But if my company pays with the company
rate, that means the amount that they pay,
then maybe they can help me
pay for these things much cheaper.
And so in the end, I make more money.
- Yeah, actually I've heard some companies
that offer great remuneration packages,
like if you have children, as you said,
they would pay for their education,
but many times they would even pay
for their childcare, like maybe a nanny.
Some of the managers
would receive maybe a
fuel bonus, so they
would get, I don't know,
$200 extra a month for fuel
for their car if they drive to work.
And so I think companies
can get a little bit creative,
and it's not that much that
they're actually spending,
but you take it as to
being a really good benefit.
- Well that's right, and
that makes you more,
I think, happy to
work for that company,
because you feel like
they're taking care of you.
Not just they're giving you money,
but they're actually taking
care of you and your family.
- That's right, so we're
actually a little bit curious
to know if how remuneration packages work
in your company or maybe in your country.
- That's right, so please let us know.
You obviously don't have to
tell us how much money you earn,
but if you wanna tell us
how these things work,
where you come from, our
website is www.englishpod.com.
We'll see you there.
- All right, bye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)